<problem display_name=" Navigating from Page to Page " group_access="{&quot;51&quot;: [1, 2]}" markdown="null">
  <p>EdX courses have many parts to them. You can find page links at the top of the site, sections and subsections in the left-hand navigation, and the Support button on the far left of your window. </p>
  <choiceresponse partial_credit="edc">
    <label>Some subsections (like this one) also have multiple pages. Where can you find the links that take you to these pages?</label>
    <description>Select all that apply.</description>
    <checkboxgroup label="Where can you find the links that take you to these pages?">
      <choice correct="true">Via the buttons in the "ribbon" at the top of the page.
      <choicehint selected="true">Right - The buttons in the "ribbon" can take you to a specific page.</choicehint>
      <choicehint selected="false">You are missing one way to get to any page you want.</choicehint></choice>
      <choice correct="true">Via the left-right arrows in the "ribbon" at the top of the page.
      <choicehint selected="true">Right - The arrows in the "ribbon" can take you to the next page or the previous page.</choicehint>
      <choicehint selected="false">You missed at least one way to get to the next page or the previous page.</choicehint></choice>
      <choice correct="true">Via the left-right arrows at the bottom of the page.
      <choicehint selected="true">Right - The arrows at the bottom of the page can take you to the next page or the previous page.</choicehint>
      <choicehint selected="false">You missed at least one way to get to the next page or the previous page.</choicehint></choice>
      <choice correct="true">Via links in the course that take you to a specific page.
      <choicehint selected="true">Right - Links you see in the course may take you to places inside the course, as well as places outside it.</choicehint>
      <choicehint selected="false">You missed at least one way to get to a specific page.</choicehint></choice>
      <compoundhint value="A B C D">That's right! All of these are correct.</compoundhint>
    </checkboxgroup>
  </choiceresponse>
  <demandhint>
    <hint>Look for these options and try them out!</hint>
    <hint>Checkbox-style problems like this one can have any number of answers correct.</hint>
  </demandhint>
</problem>
