HENRY LOUIS GATES JR.: If you can bring your true self to work,
it'll help you stay grounded.
You will never have to hide who you are because you'll
be the author of your own story every step of the way.
This will allow you to create a fulfilling and adventurous life
and career.
I'd like to ask you to remember one thing.
It's not all about you.
To succeed and live an authentic life, you should always
consider holding a space for others.
If you chart a career with meaning, you'll
also develop a diverse, interesting group of colleagues
who become your friends for life.
You're likely still early on in your journey.
The most impactful thing you can do for yourself and for others
is to be on the journey together.
One of my favorite songs from the Civil Rights movement is "This Little Light
of Mine."
CYNTHIA ERIVO: OK.
HENRY LOUIS GATES JR.: Do you happen to know it?
CYNTHIA ERIVO: I do.
Yeah.
(SINGING) This little light of mine
I'm going to let it shine
This little light of mine
Let it shine
[LAUGHS]
[APPLAUSE]
HENRY LOUIS GATES JR.: Give it up!