HENRY LOUIS GATES JR.: You have a true north all your own.
As you continue your journey, I urge you to shift your gaze inward.
Don't compare yourself to other people.
You can learn from others, but find the courage
to tailor your decisions to your own circumstances.
Let your decisions serve the real you.
You can stay true to yourself by using the tools and mindsets that we've
discussed throughout this course.
Embrace your multiple identities.
Set boundaries to protect yourself.
Develop a healthy attitude to conflict.
Ask for help.
Build authentic relationships.
Take ownership of the stereotypes and biases
that influence how others perceive you.
Be strategic and intentional about how you present yourself in the world.
As you tune into your authentic self, you'll also
become more cognizant of your purpose.
The same strategies that we've discussed in this course
will help you take the next steps in your life
and career towards relationships and activities
that have the deepest meaning for you.
Crystallizing your purpose is a long, complex, and invigorating journey,
but it starts with a curious mindset about what feels right to you.