PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Welcome to the final office hours for ChinaX.
I'm Peter Bol, and I'm here with Ted Hui who's been with you the whole semester.
And this time, we were fortunate to bring all our faculty together
who have been teaching in this course to have a group discussion.
We also asked you to let us know what pieces you particularly liked
and send in your final assessments to share them on the forum, if you chose.
The forum ran into some technical problems this past week,
and Ted, you have an update on that?
MING TAK TED HUI: Yeah.
I want to apologize for the problem in the discussion forum--
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: It's not your fault.
MING TAK TED HUI: Oh.
I mean, there were some technical issues last week.
So the width of the screen is a little bit off-centered
and the edX engineers are now trying to fix the problem.
They will give us an update as soon as possible.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: OK.
Good.
I've been really struck by the sorts of comments students have made
and the depth of learning and intelligence that they have had.
Jenny Howsam, who's been very active on the Facebook group this year,
has gotten people to talk a little about the sorts of things,
if there were favorites, right?
MING TAK TED HUI: Indeed.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: And of course, Michael Puett is always
a favorite when it comes to lecturing.
For some, the poetry of Tao Yuanming came up again and again.
MING TAK TED HUI: Sure.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: "Story of the Stone" also.
This is really in the humanities.
But I'd say Tao Yuanming, "Story of the Stone,"
these were things that resonated with a lot of people.
And also, I think there was a real appreciation for some work
that Eugene Wang, Professor Wang did on Chinese painting.
Now we also encouraged you to share your final assessment on the discussion
forum, and some people did.
Not as many of you have could, but the discussion board at the moment
isn't working very well, so that needs to be repaired.
But we've been really, really impressed by the things you've written,
and we're very glad that you have shared them.
There were some suggestions, for example,
that we ought to have a roundtable discussion in the beginning.
In fact, the faculty met together and had
an extensive discussion about what we were doing and why,
and sort of hammering out our different goals and trying to put them together.
But we didn't tape that one, the initial meeting.
MING TAK TED HUI: You should have.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Perhaps in the future-- we should have, right.
People always have asked for more, I think, than we've been able to do.
Should we be giving the whole development of Chinese poetry,
for example, through the lyric poetry?
The Song, Tang and Song.
How about the late Ming xiao shuo, the short stories,
and the long form stories, the novels?
They're there.
There's lots translated.
People should read them.
MING TAK TED HUI: Yeah.
And I mean, I got some suggestions about having a course on,
like, philosophy and religion that actually
serve as the base of those writings that we have.
And I mean, being familiar with the classical text might helped
to understand a lot of the problems we have
or the issues we encounter in the course, of the course.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Maybe we could say a few things about the things
people have shared on the forum.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to bring it up,
and I'm going to ask Ted Hui, who's been following things very, very closely,
whether he agrees with what people wrote.
And to begin with, David Doubleday commented on a piece,
a Tao Yuanming poem called "The Sixth Month--" this is for the year 408,
although Tao Yuanming didn't know it was 408--
"we had a fire."
So what's this about, and what do you think of David's comments?
MING TAK TED HUI: I think it's very interesting,
because this is a poem that comes up in Professor Tian's module.
And I think it's interesting in a sense, because he actually brings up--
I mean, he does a lot of comparison between Tao Yuanming and other writers
like a 17th century Anglo-American poet who wrote a lyric on the same topic
on encountering a fire.
A lot of the moves and a lot of techniques on that poem
is also very similar to what Tao Yuanming had done.
So it's very interesting to make that comparison.
And I think the point he's trying to make
is that how individual faces challenges or adversity, and how that, I mean,
helps us to think about what an individual is
when they're faced with difficulty.
And I think a lot of his comments, I mean, to think about what--
I mean, is there a shared humanity between people?
I mean, when they are at times of difficulty or adversity?
I mean, that itself is a very interesting take, and I would--
I mean, there are a lot of interesting things
that he mentioned, especially about facing an adversity
and trying to write about it.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: I'd like to come back, though, to this point
that I think-- it struck me as I read through these postings
that one of the things that I'm happiest about this course
is that we moved the discussion away from Chinese culture
or Chinese cultural identity to a shared human identity.
And that when we get down to the actual work in literature,
in philosophy, whatever, we actually start to read them as human beings,
and that's how they come across.
There's another famous piece by Tao Yuanming, which I remember I had to--
one of the first pieces we had to learn how to read in, I think,
second-year Literary chinese was called "The Peach Blossom Spring"
by Tao Yuanming.
This is the story where he goes into this paradise and spends time there.
Then comes out and it's centuries later, and he can't find his way back.
And Amelia Renaud writes about this as well.
MING TAK TED HUI: I think--
I mean, it's a very interesting take on the story of "The Peach Blossom
Spring."
And I think-- I mean, a lot of the observations are very--
I mean, are incredible.
I mean, the story suggests that people are naturally good in some ways,
and that when they grow up even in society rituals like hierarchy
are not taken very seriously in that piece, but it's like an ideal utopia
that they're trying to portray.
I think one interesting take there that I have doubts is that,
is this an anti-Confucian society, or is this a Confucian society
that Tao Yuanming is portraying?
Because I think it's a little bit hard for me to tell in some sense,
because we do have a utopian vision also in the Confucian--
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Oh, yes.
Is it a society with family?
MING TAK TED HUI: Mm-hmm.
Yes, indeed.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: OK.
Is it a society where there's a division of labor of some kind?
MING TAK TED HUI: Yeah.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Is it a society where there's some sense of hierarchy?
MING TAK TED HUI: Yes.
So there is--
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: It sounds to me like it's Confucian, doesn't it?
MING TAK TED HUI: Yeah.
So it's very interesting in a sense, because I mean, you do see families.
You do see, like, division of labors.
The problem is that--
I mean, so that's why when we envision a society, a utopian
society, how much of that is--
how much of that presents a society that is Confucian, and how much of that
is not?
I mean, is this a valid question, or is it--
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Well, so maybe it is--
well, I think there are two things.
One is whether you label it Confucian or not may not be the issue.
But what is the notion of utopia?
And clearly, there is a notion of a utopia,
of an ideal world in China where everyone has a place.
Everyone has a role.
There's not conflict.
There's not division.
But there's also a view that says, well, you know--
and we find this among some of the Daoist writings
that an ideal society is one where family is irrelevant, where government
is irrelevant, and things like that.
And that doesn't seem to be Tao's view.
MING TAK TED HUI: Yep.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Right.
But it's also a society which is lost.
MING TAK TED HUI: Indeed.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: We can't find it back.
MING TAK TED HUI: We can't find it back.
Exactly.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Yeah.
We want to believe in it.
It's our best dream.
MING TAK TED HUI: Yes.
So that's why I think it's very interesting in a sense that, I mean,
we think of "The Peach Blossom Spring" as a place
that is out of the empire, that escaped from the hierarchical structure that
is already at that moment in Tao Yuanming's time.
But on the other hand, I mean, when he envisioned a society, a utopian
society, there are family structures, there are still hierarchical structures
that he would want to remain.
So it's very interesting.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Right.
Right.
Everboleh talked about the painting by Zhu Da, right?
The 17th century painter called the "Fish and Fish Hawk."
So it was a painting with a fish hawk looking down at that fish
that he's about to eat.
What's that painting about?
MING TAK TED HUI: So I think everboleh used an autobiographical reading
and tried to look at the painting about that moment of eating and preying
itself resembles the moment when Zhu Da is actually being preyed by the Qing.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Preyed upon by that Qing.
MING TAK TED HUI: By the Qing.
And it's very interesting reading, because I think it actually--
I mean, trying to contextualize that painting
and trying to locate the individual voice within the painting, which
I think Professor Eugene Wang would appreciate a lot.
I mean, because it's one of the interesting aspects of those paintings.
I mean, if you read it with the biography of the painter,
then you can actually see something deeper within it.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Yeah.
So that, I think, gets an interesting issue with--
there's a general view, that Chinese poetry tends to be--
MING TAK TED HUI: Autobiographical
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Autobiographical.
The question in my mind has always been, to what extent
can that be true for paintings too?
But clearly, for some paintings, they are.
And it does strike me that this set of paintings we see in the 17th century,
not only by Zhu Da but a number of other painters
are intensely autobiographical, or commentaries on the world
that they're facing.
MING TAK TED HUI: Indeed.
Indeed.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: A poem is a poet responding to a world
that they're depicting, they're telling you about, that they're seeing.
And paintings tell you about that world they choose to see as well.
Now Jenny had a particular liking for one of the plays
by Xu Wei called "The Female Mulan Joins the Army in Place
of her Father" from a play series called the "Four Cries of a Gibbon"
by Sisheng.
Way
This was not something that was assigned,
but she has been reading herself.
She reads a book by Shiamin Kwa about it.
And Shiamin Kwa was one of our students here at Harvard, so glad
that she stayed in the school, so to speak.
What do you think of her comments on this?
MING TAK TED HUI: Her comments are fascinating,
because it's about identity and identity construction.
I mean, especially when you have, like--
I mean, because the story of Mulan is a very famous story,
because you have the Disney adaptation later in the animation version.
So I mean, a lot about cross-dressing.
Like, when a female was--
I mean, trying to replace her father to join into the army.
So there's a lot about identity and role playing.
But that itself is more complicated when it comes to a play,
because you have to--
I mean, there's an actor who has to play that role.
So they're, like, double cross-dressing within it.
So there are a lot about identity construction within that play,
and I think Jenny actually aptly pointed it out.
And I think it's really interesting in that sense.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Good.
We should let Shiamin Kwa know.
MING TAK TED HUI: Yeah.
I mean, her translation is really great.
So it's a very enjoyable read.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: And also she notes Wu Weiye's "A Lament for my Daughter"
as another thing.
Now another popular piece was the Ne-zha's story
that Professor Tian brings up, right?
And David Doubleday also writes about that.
And everboleh also writes about the story of Ne-zha.
What do you think?
MING TAK TED HUI: I think both of them actually
pointed out about the power structure or the hierarchy
within "Feng Shen Ji," within the Ne-zha section of "Feng Shen Ji."
And I think it's really interesting, because I
mean, a lot of the questions actually come
from how we think about a family that is a little bit dysfunctional.
I mean, when your father doesn't really love the son.
And I mean, how does that work when you have also another problem when
you are pushed with a lot of--
you have a more-- a broader worldview, like a Daoist, immortal worldview.
I mean, Ne-zha in that hierarchy sounds to be
a little bit superior than his father.
Then how do we deal with it?
And I think a lot of the questions and a lot of the ideas
that they have actually pointed to this question.
When you have conflicts in hierarchies, conflicts in values,
I mean, how do we think about it in terms of--
I mean, in this novel?
And I think it's interesting, because it remains as a question.
I mean, the power of Ne-zha.
Which, a lot of us actually enjoyed the story because there's a destructive
energy or a life energy within Ne-zha, which doesn't sound to us more--
I mean, confined to the Confucian family values sometimes,
because it's quite destructive too.
So how to think about that.
I mean, it's the common theme that I think both these essays pointed out,
and I think it's very interesting.
PROFESSOR PETER BOL: Good.
I think that at the heart of the humanities
is this engagement with the works of the past.
And one of the things about them is that this is--
you know, in history we distill lots of information
to try to explain how the world changed and why people made those choices that
changed things in that direction.
But I think in the humanities, and I think
this course has been a wonderful example of that--
we need to give people the opportunity to read
the world as people saw it in their own words
at the time, translated though it is.
But you know, even when we say, OK.
But here is a painting.
It's the original, right?
It's still-- we still have to translate it in some way.
We still have to be able to look and figure out,
what was the significance of this at the time to those people?
And so translation is another layer of interpretation.
But the essays you've written, the comments you've made
are also about your interpretations.
And sharing that has been tremendously valuable for us and inspiring as well.
And on behalf of all the faculty involved,
I want to express our thanks to you for being participants in this.
As teachers, ultimately, it's having engaged
students who care about the subject.
It makes all the difference.
Now I was asked a question about--
particularly since I'm going to have a bit more free time now,
if we're going to be doing more with these MOOCs on China.
You know, Harvard's been very generous to us
in allowing us to do a lot on China, but also, we've
had faculty who wanted to do it, who wanted to reach out to you.
So we actually do have another China course coming up,
but it's going to be rather different.
It's going to be my colleague Bill Kirby, with whom I taught ChinaX
originally.
I will be doing something called Doing Business
in China, which we hope to see launch probably in the fall of next year.
Maybe the summer or late spring.
And then we're going to actually have a set
of courses on the digital humanities, which
is for a professional certificate.
And this really is a very different thing from this kind of humanities,
but it is really about ways in which we can
take into account lots of information, and also represent things and visualize
things through maps, through network analysis, and so on in new ways.
But we hope some of you will eventually be with us for that
as well, although it won't be China-specific.
It will be certainly something I spend my time in.
So let us, on behalf of Ted, myself, of the faculty, Meghan Morrissey who's
been sort of behind the scenes, guiding this course,
let me thank you all for joining us.
And we look forward to hearing more from you through Facebook
or through later courses on HarvardX.